Philip K. Crowe Papers MS109
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Philip K. Crowe Papers
1800 -- 1981
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Crowe, Philip Kingsland
MS109
52.4 Linear Feet
36 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Correspondence and subject files; Writing and research notes; Embassy, government, and military papers; Photographs; Personal ephemera and memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
Philip K. Crowe, an American diplomat, conservationist, and author was a trustee of the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy at Tufts University.
Philip Kingsland Crowe was born January 7, 1908 in New York City, the son of Earl and Kathleen McClellan (Higgins) Crowe. Following his graduation from the University of Virginia, Crowe began his long career as a reporter at the New York Evening Post in 1933. From 1935 to 1937 Crowe was an explorer and big game hunter in French Indo-China. In 1937 he married his first wife Irene Pettus with whom he had three children: Phillippa, Irene, and Mary.
Crowe spent the next several years working in advertising first for Life magazine and later for Fortune magazine until the start of World War II. From 1941 to 1944 he served as the chief of secret intelligence for the Office of Strategic Services in the China-Burma-India theater. Following the war, Crowe returned to his position on the advertising staff of Fortune magazine.
Crowe began his diplomatic career in 1948 as the American special representative of the Economic Administration in China. In 1953, he received his first ambassadorial appointment as United States Ambassador to Ceylon, now Sri Lanka, where he served until 1956. In 1954 he was also the United States delegate to the Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East. Following his term as Ambassador to Ceylon, Crowe served as the special assistant to Secretary of State John Foster Dulles from 1957 to 1959.
Following his term as United States Ambassador to the Union of South Africa, from 1959 to 1961, Crowe, an avid conservationist, led six Wildlife Missions during the 1960's for the World Wildlife Fund. Crowe had been a director of the World Wildlife Fund and a member of the advisory council of the African Wildlife Leadership Foundation. Crowe wrote six books on nature and wildlife.
Crowe returned to the diplomatic service as the United States Ambassador to Norway from 1969 to 1973. This was immediately followed by a term as the United States Ambassador to Denmark from 1973 to 1975. In 1975, Crowe married his second wife Suzanne Noregaard with whom he had one daughter, Clara, and he retired from diplomatic service.
Crowe received numerous honors during his lifetime. He was awarded a Bronze star, the Order of Yun-Hui from the Republic of China, and the Grand Cross of St. Olav from Norway. He was also made an Officer in the French Legion of Honor and a Grand Official in the Military Order of Christ.
Crowe died October 16, 1976 at his home in Easton, Maryland following a heart attack.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains personal papers relating to the life and career of Ambassador Philip Kingsland Crowe. Materials are organized in five series: Photographs; Writings and Research Notes; Embassy, Government, and Military Papers; Correspondence and Subject Files; and Personal Ephemera and Memorabilia. The bulk of the material dates to Crowe's diplomatic career spanning from 1950 to 1975.
Custodial History
Amabassador Crowe began the pocess of delivering his books and papers to the library of the Fletcher School of Diplomacy, Tufts University, during his lifetime. After his death in 1976, his executor, three of his daughters, Phillippa Crowe Neilson, Irene Crowe, and Mary Crowe, and his former wife, Irene Pettus Crowe, as well as the Pettus-Crowe Foundation, Inc., joined together to complete the intended gift.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was transferred to DCA by Ginn Library in June 2004.
Foreign affairs
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1953 -- 1975; 1950 -- 1975; MS109.001; 32.4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series primarily consists of correspondence written to Crowe from individuals, clubs and organizations approximately between 1950 and 1975. In some cases, a typed copy of Crowe's letter to the correspondent is also included. Correspondents include major political figures, members of the diplomatic community, key figures in wildlife preservation, and foreign heads of state. Some notable figures of interest include President Richard Nixon, President Gerald Ford, John Ausland, John Merrill Olin, and John Moors Cabot, whose papers are also housed in the Digital Collections and Archives. The files are arranged in an alphabetical run from A-Z by the correspondent's last name, with subject files such as European Trips and Norway, Horse interspersed in the alphabetical series. No attempt was made to alter the original order of the files when they arrived at the archives.
  There are occasional exceptions to the alphabetical order. For instance, at the beginning of the T section is a group of files labeled Travel. These files document trips taken by Crowe both abroad and in the United States. They are arranged by destination, and contain items such as letters, itineraries, and notes. Another group of files exists outside of the alphabetical run and are located at the beginning of the W section. The first part of this group of files is labeled Wildlife, and the second half is labeled World Wildlife Fund. The Wildlife files relate to various wildlife preservation groups and societies and primarily contain correspondence. The World Wildlife Fund files concern Crowe's work for the World Wildlife Fund, and contain correspondence, reports, and committee meeting minutes.
  Also, at the end of the alphabetical run there are a series of files arranged chronologically containing copies of Crowe's unclassified personal embassy correspondence. These files cover his tenure as ambassador to Norway from 1969 to 1973 and as ambassador to Denmark from 1973 to 1975. Within the files the correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order. Following the chronological correspondence files are a series of files containing correspondence relating to Crowe's campaign for the post of ambassador to Ceylon.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Norway Embassy Correspondence: Achille-Anderson, MS109.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Adams, MS109.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Easton, MD Personal Correspondence: Adams-Attwood, MS109.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Denmark Embassy Correspondence: Aebel-Fedosky, MS109.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Woodstock, VT Personal Correspondence: Albuiget-Ayer, MS109.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Aldrich-Arundel, MS109.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Republic of South Africa Embassy Correspondence: Alford-deBarros, MS109.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Sri Lanka Embassy Correspondence: Allison-Austin, MS109.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - UK Embassy Correspondence: Agnew-Barclay, MS109.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Norway Embassy Correspondence: Bob Anderson, MS109.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Norway Embassy Correspondence: Angelo-Ateigen, MS109.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Anglers Club of New York, MS109.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Asia Society, MS109.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Atlantic Salmon Association, MS109.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Atlantic Salmon, MS109.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Atlantic Salmon, MS109.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Restoration of Atlantic Salmon in America, Inc., MS109.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Atlantic Salmon: Committee on Emergency, MS109.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Norway Embassy Correspondence: Ausland, MS109.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Misc. A, MS109.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Bal-Barb, MS109.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Barn-Beli, MS109.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Bell-Bernh, MS109.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Bernt-Biss, MS109.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Bix-Bod, MS109.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Bogdan-Breutanos, MS109.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Borel-Brett, MS109.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Briggs (1 of 3), MS109.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Briggs (2 of 3), MS109.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Briggs (3 of 3), MS109.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Bringle-Bry, MS109.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Buchanan-Bush, MS109.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Butt-Byron, MS109.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Bachrach, Duck Blind and Blue Shield, MS109.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Barre Publishing Co., MS109.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Boats and Business Council, MS109.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Book Review of the "Empty Ark", MS109.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Boone and Crockett Club, MS109.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: The Chronicle of the Horse, MS109.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Cabot-Carey, MS109.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Carden-Carlsrud, MS109.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Carter-Chadwyck, MS109.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Chafer-Christophersen, MS109.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Clark-Cleveland, MS109.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Coffin, MS109.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Cohen-Coolidge, MS109.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Coolidge-Corzo, MS109.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: Courshon-Crene, MS109.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Crane-Cuylo, MS109.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, MS109.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Clubs, MS109.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Clubs, MS109.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Coolidge Correspondence, MS109.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Contacts, Misc., MS109.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: DACOR Bulletin, MS109.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Dagan-Davis, MS109.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Davison-deRemer, MS109.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Deraniyagala-Deverell, MS109.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Dexter-Donovan, MS109.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Dorian-Dudley, MS109.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Dugdale-Dyrkoren, MS109.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Diplomatic Corps, MS109.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Dogs, MS109.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Eagleburger-Eldredge, MS109.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Elizur-Emmons, MS109.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Enders-Engelhard, MS109.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Engh-Exter, MS109.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - The Explorers Club, MS109.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - European Trips, MS109.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Fagan-Field, MS109.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Fields-Ford, MS109.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Forman-Franklin, MS109.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Fraser-Funston, MS109.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: The Faeroes Islands, MS109.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Farming, Food, and Falcons, MS109.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: The Field Magazine, MS109.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: Fly Fisher's Club, MS109.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Organizations, Clubs, Etc.: F, MS109.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gab-Gar, MS109.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gar-Gas, MS109.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gat-Gee, MS109.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gee-Gene, MS109.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Geo-Gib, MS109.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gie-Gil, MS109.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gil-Goone, MS109.001.006.00014 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Goo-Gran, MS109.001.006.00015 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Gran-Grant, MS109.001.006.00016 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Grant-Green, MS109.001.006.00017 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: Green-Gron, MS109.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Gross-Gune, MS109.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Gunn-Guy, MS109.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Guests, MS109.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Guests, MS109.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Guests, MS109.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Haa-Hal, MS109.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Hal-Ham, MS109.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Ham-Han, MS109.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Harrigan-Harris, MS109.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Hartke-Hatters, MS109.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Hau-Hel, MS109.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Har-Hark, MS109.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Heal-Henn, MS109.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Henry-Hibberts, MS109.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Herter, MS109.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hichens-Hicks, MS109.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Heller-Helms, MS109.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Higgins-Hildreth, MS109.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hill, MS109.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hill-Hillenbrand, MS109.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hilson, MS109.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Him-Hof, MS109.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hohle-Holt, MS109.001.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Holton, MS109.001.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Holy-Hong, MS109.001.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hook-Horn, MS109.001.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Host-How, MS109.001.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Howey-Hunt, MS109.001.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Hun-Hyerdal, MS109.001.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - Holy Land Conservation Fund, MS109.001.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Iba-Ing, MS109.001.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: Ings-Intelligence, MS109.001.008.00021 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: International, MS109.001.008.00022 (Box 8)
  - Invitations-Accepted, MS109.001.008.00023 (Box 8)
  - Invitations-Accepted, MS109.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Regrets, MS109.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Declined, MS109.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Regrets, MS109.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Regrets, MS109.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Declined, MS109.001.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Declined, MS109.001.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Invitations-Declined, MS109.001.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Ich-Iver, MS109.001.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Jackson-Jeho, MS109.001.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Jenkins-Jennings, MS109.001.009.00011 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Jequier-Johnson, MS109.001.009.00012 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Johnson, MS109.001.009.00013 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Jon, MS109.001.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Jordan-Julton, MS109.001.009.00015 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Kai-Shek-Kelley, MS109.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Kellog, MS109.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Kellog, MS109.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Kellog, MS109.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Kemp-Kleberg, MS109.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Klein, MS109.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Kleppe-Kototawan, MS109.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Krag-Kvall, MS109.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: LaBastille-Lamb, MS109.001.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Lamb, MS109.001.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Lampe-Lapham, MS109.001.010.00011 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Lapham, MS109.001.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence: Lakota Club, MS109.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lapstun-Lawrence, MS109.001.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lawrence, MS109.001.011.00003 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lea-Leavitt, MS109.001.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - Lectures, Folder 1, MS109.001.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - Lectures, Folder 2, MS109.001.011.00006 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lederer-LeRoux, MS109.001.011.00007 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Leshem-Libich, MS109.001.011.00008 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Liddell-Lima, MS109.001.011.00009 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lind-Lipton, MS109.001.011.00010 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lissanovitch-Loomis, MS109.001.011.00011 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Looram-Lorentzen, MS109.001.011.00012 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Louw-Lundy, MS109.001.011.00013 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: Lunnford-Lyon, MS109.001.011.00014 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: L-unlabeled last name, MS109.001.011.00015 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence: MacArthur-MacMillan, MS109.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: MacNaughton-Macomber, MS109.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: MacPhail, MS109.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Macrae-Mallinson, MS109.001.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Malone-Mapel, MS109.001.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Maps, MS109.001.012.00006 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Marburg-Martin, MS109.001.012.00007 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Martonmere-Mathias, MS109.001.012.00008 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Mathiesen, MS109.001.012.00009 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Mathieson-McClintock, MS109.001.012.00010 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: McCloskey-McIntosh, MS109.001.012.00011 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: McIntosh-McKernan, MS109.001.012.00012 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: McKneally-Meloy, MS109.001.012.00013 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Memorials-Meyer, MS109.001.012.00014 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Michael-Middendorf, MS109.001.012.00015 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence: Middleton-Milks, MS109.001.013.00001 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Milks-Milks, MS109.001.013.00002 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Milks-Mjelde, MS109.001.013.00003 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Mo-Montagu, MS109.001.013.00004 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Montoya-Morris, MS109.001.013.00005 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Morrison-Murphy, MS109.001.013.00006 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Murphy-Mysore, MS109.001.013.00007 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Nalle-Nato, MS109.001.013.00008 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Natua-Naude, MS109.001.013.00009 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Naval-Neville, MS109.001.013.00010 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Newhold-Newnan, MS109.001.013.00011 (Box 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1970; MS109.001.013.00012 (Box 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1970 -- 1972; MS109.001.013.00013 (Box 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1959 -- 1975; MS109.001.013.00014 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence: Newton-Nicholson, MS109.001.014.00001 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Nielsen-Nilssen, MS109.001.014.00002 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Nissen-Norton, MS109.001.014.00003 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Norway Letters, MS109.001.014.00004 (Box 14)
  - Norway (Horses), MS109.001.014.00005 (Box 14)
  - Norway, North, MS109.001.014.00006 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Norwegian-Nylund, MS109.001.014.00007 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Oater-O'Connor, MS109.001.014.00008 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: O'Connor-Olan, MS109.001.014.00009 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Olds-Orbin, MS109.001.014.00010 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Ortisland-Ostimen, MS109.001.014.00011 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Olin, MS109.001.014.00012 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Olin, MS109.001.014.00013 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence: Olin, MS109.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Olin, MS109.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Oslo, MS109.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: OSS, MS109.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Oxford, MS109.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Pai-Parson, MS109.001.015.00006 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Parson-Parton, MS109.001.015.00007 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Paterson-Peck, MS109.001.015.00008 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Peder-Perriman, MS109.001.015.00009 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Pepper-Percy, MS109.001.015.00010 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Perenia-Perkins, MS109.001.015.00011 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Perkins-Pettins, MS109.001.015.00012 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Pettins-Phelps, MS109.001.015.00013 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Pfeffermann, MS109.001.015.00014 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Phelps, MS109.001.015.00015 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence: Phillipi-Phillips, MS109.001.016.00001 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Phillips-Platt, MS109.001.016.00002 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Platon-Plichon, MS109.001.016.00003 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Plumley-Pope, MS109.001.016.00004 (Box 16)
  - Polar Bears, MS109.001.016.00005 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Porter-Prend, MS109.001.016.00006 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Pret-Purachatra, MS109.001.016.00007 (Box 16)
  - Press Clips, MS109.001.016.00008 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Rab-Rav, MS109.001.016.00009 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Raw-Read, MS109.001.016.00010 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Read-Redcliffe, MS109.001.016.00011 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Redcliffe-Reed, MS109.001.016.00012 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Reese-Reese, MS109.001.016.00013 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Reese-Reese, MS109.001.016.00014 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Reese-Reese, MS109.001.016.00015 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Reeves-Reid, MS109.001.016.00016 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence: Reiner-Replogle, MS109.001.016.00017 (Box 16)
  - Republican, MS109.001.017.00001 (Box 17)
  - Restoration of Atlantic Salmon, MS109.001.017.00002 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Reston-Rhodesia, MS109.001.017.00003 (Box 17)
  - Rhodesia, MS109.001.017.00004 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Riahi-Riopelle, MS109.001.017.00005 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Riordan-Ripley, MS109.001.017.00006 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Ripley-Rippin, MS109.001.017.00007 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Rippin-Roberts, MS109.001.017.00008 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Roberts-Roberts, MS109.001.017.00009 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Roberts-Roberts, MS109.001.017.00010 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Rocke-Rogers, MS109.001.017.00011 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Rogers-Ronning, MS109.001.017.00012 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Romanowski-Roosevelt, MS109.001.017.00013 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Roosevelt-Rosenlew, MS109.001.017.00014 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Ross-Rountree, MS109.001.017.00015 (Box 17)
  - Royal Copenhagen Shooting Society, MS109.001.017.00016 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Rountree-Rugg, MS109.001.017.00017 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Rumack-Rupert, MS109.001.017.00018 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Royal Norwegian-Ryan, MS109.001.017.00019 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Rupinski-Ryan, MS109.001.017.00020 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Ryan-, MS109.001.017.00021 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence: Sab-Sai, MS109.001.018.00001 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Saint, MS109.001.018.00002 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Saith-Samis, MS109.001.018.00003 (Box 18)
  - Salmon, MS109.001.018.00004 (Box 18)
  - Salmon, MS109.001.018.00005 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Salol-Sang, MS109.001.018.00006 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Sang-Sarn, MS109.001.018.00007 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Sat-Sav, MS109.001.018.00008 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Schae-Schaf, MS109.001.018.00009 (Box 18)
  - Schedules, MS109.001.018.00010 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Sche-Schi, MS109.001.018.00011 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Schiller, MS109.001.018.00012 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Schoe-School, MS109.001.018.00013 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: School (SAIS), MS109.001.018.00014 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: School (SAIS)-Schooley, MS109.001.018.00015 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence: Schou-Schwo, MS109.001.018.00016 (Box 18)